Guide to the Office of the Registrar records, 1822-2005 RG0041
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Office of the Registrar records
1822-2006
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of the Registrar
RG0041
8.25 Linear Feet
Collection includes class schedules, reports of the Registrar, correspondence, and memos.
Restrictions on Access
Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Student records in Series 1 are closed for 100 years from date of record creation.
Series 2 is closed to research for 50 years from date of record creation.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired through transfers from Office of the Registrar.
Historical Note
The Office of the Registrar at the George Washington University maintains all academic records and issues official transcripts. It also provides certification of enrollment documents (for loan deferments, Social Security benefits, health insurance or other services) and verification of degrees earned at GW. Before 1929 the Registrar was also the admissions officer for the University. Since the fall of 1981 student records have been maintained electronically; records prior to fall 1981 are on microfilm. Instructional staff may have access to these records at the Registrar's Office.
The Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) prohibits the disclosure of student records to unauthorized parties. Access to student information is granted only to individuals who have the student's written permission, to parents who can demonstrate that they can claim the student as a dependent for income tax purposes, and in response to a valid subpoena as provided by FERPA. The Registrar's Office does, however, release directory information. According to the Guide to Student Rights and Responsibilities, Section III, Disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information from Student Records, directory information includes: name, local address and telephone number; name and address of next of kin; dates of attendance; school or division of enrollment; field of study; credit hours earned; degrees earned; honors received; weight, height, and age of members of athletic teams; and participation in organizations and activities chartered or otherwise established by the University, including intercollegiate athletics.
Federal law also entitles students to review their scholastic records at all levels. This includes a student's right to review letters of reference written by faculty unless this right is expressly waived. University policy prohibits faculty to require such a waiver as a condition for writing a reference.
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include class schedules, reports of the Registrar, correspondence, and memos. This material ranges in date from 1822-2006, and was transferred to the University Archives by the University Registrar. Note: Not all series are processed. Ask staff for assistance.
Collection Organization
Organized into five series: Office files, Office files, Class schedules, Enrollment reports and degrees conferred, and Reports.
Washington (D.C.); George Washington University
- Office files, 1822-1979; RG0041 Series 1; 0.25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Access to student records is governed by the federal Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), which protects the privacy of student education records. Student records are closed for 100 years from date of record creation.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes forms, flyers, brochures, questionnaire, memorandums, recites, grades, a report correspondence, statistics, and announcements. They range in date from 1822 to 1979. The materials concern grading forms, classes, registration, student bills, identification, telephone directory, the summer advanced registration program, student body information for 1963 to 1964, and published students by year and department.
  - Registrar's Office, 02/01/1926-09/01/1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Registrar's Office--Publications, 10/02/1905 -04/18/1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Registrar's Office--Registration Statistics (1822-1861) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Students, 07/20/1939-1978 ca. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Office files, 1975-1991; RG0041 Series 2; 1.5 Linear feet
  This series contains correspondence and memos, report (1976) on the Committee on Veteran's Affairs in the U.S. Senate. The material dates from 1975-91.
  - Correspondence and memos, report (1976) on the Committee on Veteran's Affairs in the U.S. Senate, 1975-1991; RG0041 Series 2 (Box 1)
- Schedules of classes, 1930-2006; RG0041 Series 3; 4 Linear feet (Box 4, Box 2, Box 3, Box 1)
  This series consists class schedules, which also includes in earlier years faculty offices and campus maps. They range in date from 1930-2006. The print edition of the Schedule of Classes was discontinued in 2007. All subsequent schedules are published online.
  - Class schedules, 1930-1935 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Class schedules, 1935-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Class schedules, 1939-1943 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Class schedules, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Class schedules, 1954-1947 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Class schedules, 1947-1949 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Class schedules, 1949-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Class schedules, 1951-1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Class schedules, 1953-1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Class schedules, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Class schedules, 1957-1959 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Class schedules, 1959-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Class schedules, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Class schedules, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Class schedules, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Class schedules, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Class schedules, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Class schedules, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Class schedules, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Class schedules, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Class schedules, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Class schedules, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Class schedules, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Class schedules, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Class schedules, 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Class schedules, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Class schedules, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Class schedules, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1983 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1986 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1986 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1988 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1990 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1990 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1991 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Class schedules: Summer/Fall 1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1992 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Class schedules: Summer/Fall 1992 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1993 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Class schedules: Off-campus Graduate Spring 1994 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Class schedules: Off-campus, Summer 1995 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1995 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Class schedules: Fall 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1996 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1996 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Class schedules: Fall/Revised Fall 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Class schedules: Spring/Revised Spring 1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Class schedules: Fall Revised Fall 1997 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Class schedules: Spring 1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Class schedules: Preliminary/Revised Fall 1998 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Class schedules: Preliminary Spring 1999 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Class schedules: Summer 1999 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Class schedules: Preliminary Fall 1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Class schedules: Preliminary/Final Spring 2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Class schedules: Summer 2000 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Class schedules: Preliminary/Final Fall 2000 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Class schedules: Preliminary/Final Spring 2001 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Class schedules: Summer 2001 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Class schedules: Off-campus Graduate Summer 2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Class schedules: Preliminary/Final Fall 2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Class schedules: Spring 2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Class schedules: Summer 2002 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Class schedules: Off-campus Graduate Summer 2002 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Class schedules: Fall 2002 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Class schedules: Spring 2003 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Class schedules: Summer 2003 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Class schedules: Fall 2003 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Class schedules: Spring 2004 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Class schedules: Summer 2004 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Class schedules: Fall 2004 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Class schedules: Spring 2005 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Class schedules: Fall 2005 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Class schedules: Spring 2006 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Enrollment reports and degrees conferred, 1986-1992; RG0041 Series 4; 1.5 Linear feet (Box 1)
  This series contains enrollment reports and degrees conferred and dates from 1986-92.
- Reports of the registrar, 1953-1975; RG0041 Series 5; 1 Linear feet (Box 2, Box 1)
  This series contains reports of the registrar, and range in date from 1953-75.
  - Report of the registrar, 1953-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Report of the registrar, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    General note
    2 copies
  - Report of the registrar, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Report of the registrar, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Report of the registrar, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Report of the registrar, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    3 copies
  - Report of the registrar, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Report of the registrar, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Report of the registrar, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Report of the registrar, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Report of the registrar, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Report of the registrar, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Reports of the registrar, 1927-1979; RG0041 Series 6; 9 Linear Feet 6 record center boxes
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains reports from the registrar from 1921-1979. The data captured in this collection will appeal to researchers interested in tracking trends spanning six decades regarding degrees conferred, number of students per school, their gender and their state or country of origin. Also included are complete lists of professors and associate professors and the courses they taught per semester.
  - Reports of the registrar, 1927-1948 (Box 1)
  - Reports of the registrar, 1948-1966 (Box 2)
  - Reports of the registrar, 1964-1972 (Box 3)
  - Reports of the registrar, 1972-1976 (Box 4)
  - Reports of the registrar, 1976-1977 (Box 5)
  - Reports of the registrar, 1977-1979 (Box 6)